BU Records: Donald I. Moore, Inclusive: 1935-2003; Bulk: 1948-1979
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Donald I. Moore
Inclusive: 1935-2003; Bulk: 1948-1979
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/383
Moore, Donald I., 1910 -
5 document boxes, 5 record storage boxes, and 5 oversized boxes.
BU Records: Donald I. Moore contains correspondence from World War II, general correspondence relating to Moore's compositions and Moore's work as the director of the Golden Wave Band at Baylor University, marching band diagrams, photographic materials, programs, and film of the Golden Wave Band's performances.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Donald I. Moore (1910-1998) was born in Farnhamville, Iowa, on 1910 April 11. He graduated from North Des Moines (Iowa) High School; attended Drake University for one year; received his B.A. degree from Carleton College in Northfield, Minnesota, in 1932, and his M.A. degree from Colorado State College of Education in 1940. After directing high school bands in Iowa at Charles City and Britt, he moved to Dallas, Texas, where he directed school bands and the all-city orchestra until he was named Director of Bands at Colorado State College of Education in January 1941. Moore served in the U.S. Navy from 1942 to 1945. After his service, he completed his Ed.D. degree at the University of Michigan, and then went to New York City for a year as director of bands at both the Juilliard School of Music and Columbia University. In September 1948, he became Director of Bands at Baylor University.
Moore was a Professor of Music and Director Emeritus of Bands at Baylor, where he directed the Golden Wave Band from 1948 to 1969. During Moore’s 20-year tenure, the band accompanied the football team to bowl appearances, represented Baylor at Baptist meetings around the world and grew to 135 members, more than tripling the size of the original Golden Wave Band. While at Baylor, Moore also became nationally recognized as a composer, conductor, clinician, and adjudicator of bands throughout the United States. Over thirty of his compositions have been published, and some of his concert marches are played by bands all over the world. The best known of these are: "Marcho Poco," "Ides of March," "Dawn of Peace," "March Forth," and "Rise and Shine."
Scope and Content
BU Records: Donald I. Moore is arranged into six series: I. Correspondence, II. Golden Wave Band, III. Printed Materials, IV. Film Reels, V. Photographic Materials, and VI. Artifacts. The first series of Correspondence contains letters to and from Donald Moore. A quarter of the correspondence are scans of original letters and are in excellent condition. The other correspondence in the series are original and are in good condition with minor tears and creases. The second series Golden Wave Band is compiled of notes and paraphernalia related to Moore's tenure with the Golden Wave Band. This series is in good condition, as the notebooks and marching formations have few tears and creases. The posters and flyers for the Golden Wave Band are slightly damaged on the sides and ends. The third series of Printed Materials contains a wide variety of items from Moore's involvement with Baylor University, his tenure as director of the Golden Wave Band, and his leadership and participation with various organizations. The series is in good condition. The fourth series of Film Reels is from Moore's tenure as director of the Golden Wave Band. The condition of this series is unknown. The fifth series of Photographic Materials is from Moore's directorship of the Golden Wave Band. An oversize box of photographic slides is also included. All are in excellent condition. The final series of Artifacts is composed of items from Moore's time with the Golden Wave Band and his participation in the fraternity Kappa Kappa Psi. All of these items are in good condition.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, various materials in the BU Records: Donald I. Moore collection were arranged by material type. Manuscripts were arranged in folders with titles, no dates, while tapes, photographs, photographic slides, and artifacts were originally placed in unmarked boxes.
Currently, the collection is arranged in six series: I. Correspondence, II. Golden Wave Band, III. Printed Materials, IV. Film Reels, V. Photographic Materials, and VI. Artifacts. Within each folder, materials were kept in original order, which is not necessarily chronological order. Tapes, photographs, photographic slides, and artifacts have been placed in appropriate housing for the nature of the materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/383. Acquired 2014-05-30
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Moore, Donald I.
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Football.; Baylor University -- History -- 20th century.; Baylor University -- School of Music.; Baylor University. Golden Wave Band.
Subjects
Band music.; Baylor University -- Faculty.; Marches (Band)
Genres
Certificates.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Directories.; Film reels.; Membership lists.; Photographs.; Posters.; Programs.; Slides (photographs)
- Correspondence, 1943-1979; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains letters from Donald Moore to his wife, Norma Moore, during his service in World War II, letters involving his work as band director of the Baylor University Golden Wave Band, and his letters to colleagues and music production companies. The series is in good condition. The letters from WWII are all scans of the original letters and are in pristine condition. The other correspondence in the series is original and the majority have some tears and creases.
  - World War II (1 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - World War II (2 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - World War II (3 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - World War II (4 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - World War II (5 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - World War II (6 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - World War II (7 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - World War II (8 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - World War II (9 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - World War II (10 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - World War II (11 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - World War II (12 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - World War II (13 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - World War II (14 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - World War II (15 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - World War II (16 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - World War II (17 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - World War II (18 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - World War II (19 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - World War II (20 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - World War II (21 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - World War II (22 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - World War II (23 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - World War II (24 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - World War II (25 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - World War II (26 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - World War II (27 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - World War II (28 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - World War II (29 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - World War II (30 of 30), 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General (1 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General (2 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General (3 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General (4 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General (5 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General (6 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General (7 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General (8 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General (9 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General (10 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General (11 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General (12 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - General (13 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General (14 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General (15 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General (16 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - General (17 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - General (18 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General (19 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - General (20 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General (21 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - General (22 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General (23 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - General (24 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General (25 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - General (26 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - General (27 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General (28 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - General (29 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - General (30 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - General (31 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - General (32 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - General (33 of 33), 1948-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1966 Tour, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Baylor Music Band Camp, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1965 Tour, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miama-BWA, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Golden Wave Band, 1949-1979; 2
  This series contains marching formations, Moore's director notebooks, roll call, posters, and flyers from Moore's tenure as director of the Golden Wave Band. Moore was a Professor of Music and is Director Emeritus of Bands at Baylor University, where he directed the bands from 1948 to 1969. This series is in good condition, the notebooks and marching formations have minor tears and creases. The posters and flyers for the Golden Wave Band are slightly bent and damaged on the sides and ends.
  - General, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - General, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - General, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - General, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - General, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - General, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - General, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - General, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - General, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - General, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - General, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - General, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - General, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Performance Plans (1 of 6), 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Performance Plans (2 of 6), 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Performance Plans (3 of 6), 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Performance Plans (4 of 6), 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Performance Plans (5 of 6), 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Performance Plans (6 of 6), 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Concert Programs (1 of 2), 1949-1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Concert Programs (2 of 2), 1949-1968 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Golden Wave Club, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Golden Wave Banquet, 1973-1979 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Marching Formations (1 of 2), 1956, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Marching Formations (2 of 2), 1956, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "That Good Old Baylor Line", undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Posters, 1957, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Printed Materials, 1939-2003; 3
  General condition: Good.
  The series contains a wide variety of items: sheet music, program booklets, roll call, clippings, and notes. The majority of these focus on Moore's involvement with Baylor University, his tenure as the director of the Golden Wave Band, and his leadership and participation with various organizations, including the American Bandmasters Association and Kappa Psi, the National Honorary Band Fraternity. Moore was Grand President of Kappa Kappa Psi from 1955 to 1957. In 1969, he was given Kappa Kappa Psi's highest honor, the Distinguished Service to Music Award.
  The series is in good condition. The sheet music has a few rips and tears on the sides and edges. The programs, booklets, and notes are all well preserved, with minor tears and creases.
  - Booklets (1 of 3), 1968-1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Booklets (2 of 3), 1968-1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Booklets (3 of 3), 1968-1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - General, 1946-1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - University of Southern Mississippi Symphonic Band Program, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - American Bandmasters Association Convention (1 of 2), 1977-1994 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - American Bandmasters Association Convention (2 of 2), 1977-1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - All University Sing programs, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Seventh and James Baptist Church, 1955-1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Columbus Avenue Baptist Church, 1973-1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 45th Annual Mid-West International Band and Orchestra Clinic, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Andrew White - Farewell Recital Tour, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Music Hour, 1974-1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Baylor Wind Ensemble, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Baylor Wind Ensemble Camp, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Baylor Symphony Orchestra, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Baylor Opera Theatre, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Waco Symphony Association (1 of 2), 1973-1979 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Waco Symphony Association (2 of 2), 1973-1979 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - School of Music Faculty Recital Programs, 1956-1979 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - School of Music Distinguished Artist Series, 1974-1978 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - School of Music Student Recitals, 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Festival of Contemporary Music, 1965-1969 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - U.S. Navy Band, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Workbook for Band Scoring, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Football Programs, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "The Compositions of Donald I. Moore", undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Juilliard Band, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Mid-West International Band and Orchestra Clinic, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - National Music Publishers' Association, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Strecker Museum, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Class Records (1 of 2) [RESTRICTED], 1947, 1971-1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Class Records (2 of 2) [RESTRICTED], 1947, 1971-1979 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Roll Book (1 of 2), 1937-1941 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Roll Book (2 of 2), 1937-1941 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Contents of Binder: Programs, 1954-1974 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Contents of Binder: Class Notes (1 of 2), 1954 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Contents of Binder: Class Notes (2 of 2), 1954 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (1 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (2 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (3 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (4 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (5 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (6 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (7 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (8 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (9 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (10 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (11 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (12 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (13 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (14 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Kappa Kappa Psi (15 of 15), 1939-2003 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - American Bandmasters Association Directory, 1966-2001 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Programs (1 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Programs (2 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Programs (3 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Programs (4 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Programs (5 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Programs (6 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Programs (7 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Programs (8 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Programs (9 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Programs (10 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Programs (11 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Programs (12 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Programs (13 of 13), 1939-1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Guggenheim Memorial Concerts (1 of 6), 1961-1975 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The Guggenheim Memorial Concerts (2 of 6), 1961-1975 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Guggenheim Memorial Concerts (3 of 6), 1961-1975 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Guggenheim Memorial Concerts (4 of 6), 1961-1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - The Guggenheim Memorial Concerts (5 of 6), 1961-1975 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Guggenheim Memorial Concerts (6 of 6), 1961-1975 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (1 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Clippings (2 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Clippings (3 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (4 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (5 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (6 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (7 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (8 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (9 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (10 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (11 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (12 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (13 of 13), 1948-1967 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Sheet Music (1 of 3), undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Sheet Music (2 of 3), undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Sheet Music (3 of 3), undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - "Golden Wave" Sheet Music, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "Green and Gold" Sheet Music, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "Mighty Bears" Sheet Music, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Band Banquet Programs, 1959-1963 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Memorials to Don (1 of 3), 1998 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Memorials to Don (2 of 3), 1998 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Memorials to Don (3 of 3), 1998 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - General, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Game Day Memorabilia, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1950-1969 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Film Reels, 1951-1967; 4
  General condition: Unknown.
  This series contains numerous film reels documenting Moore's tenure as band director of the Golden Wave Band at Baylor University. Nearly all of the tapes are labeled with dates and which football game they correspond to. The condition of the film is unknown. Some have been labeled by a prior processor and state they have color but no sound, while others are black and white.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  16 mm motion picture film; 8 mm motion picture
  - Film Reels (1 of 3), 1951-1967 (Box 19 OVZ)
  - Film Reels (2 of 3), 1951-1967 (Box 20 OVZ)
  - Film Reels (3 of 3), 1951-1967 (Box 21 OVZ)
- Photographic Materials, 1950-1965; 5
  This series contains photographs from Moore's tenure as director of the Golden Wave Band. Images depict many of his marching band formations. The photographs are in excellent condition, with no decomposition and only minor tears and creases. An oversize box of photographic slides is also included in this series. Many of the slides have titles and dates to identify them.
  Photographic print
  - Photographs (1 of 2), 1950-1955, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Photographs (2 of 2), 1950-1955, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Photographs (1 of 2), undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Photographs ( 2 of 2), undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Photographic Material, undated (Box [1062], Folder 1)
  - Photographic Slides, undated (Box 22 OVZ)
- Artifacts, undated; 6
  This series contains items from Moore's tenure as director of the Golden Wave Band at Baylor University and his participation in the fraternity Kappa Kappa Psi. It contains: Moore's director's coat, Kappa Kappa Psi pins, an award from Kappa Kappa Psi, and plaques from Baylor University and Kappa Kappa Psi. All of these items are in good condition, with minor wear and tear. The plaques are in excellent condition.
  - Artifacts, undated (Box 23 OVZ)